# Chelhwon Kim

Palo Alto, CA 94306 • cheolhwon.kim@gmail.com

**Computer Vision Researcher** with over 6 years of experience in a wide range of computer vision projects, including indoor 3D reconstruction and localization, cross-domain mapping, digital human creation, and remote assistance systems. Excited about the opportunity to contribute my skills and enthusiasm for innovation to a collaborative research team.

# Experience

OCTOBER 2021 - PRESENT

### Associate Staff Research Engineer | SONY R&D Center US Lab | San Jose, California

Working on 3DCG digital human creation, optimizing 3D reconstruction processes, and developing innovative capture and modeling techniques to enhance efficiency and realism in digital content creation.

AUGUST 2020 - OCTOBER 2021

# Computer Vision Engineer | Leia Inc. | Palo Alto, California

Designed and implemented advanced computer vision models for content classification and depth enhancement.

APRIL 2016 - JUNE 2020

# Senior Research Scientist | FX (Fuji Xerox) Palo Alto Lab | Palo Alto, California

Developed computer vision and deep learning algorithms for HCI systems, including indoor localization for tracking people, image to audio translation, tabletop telepresence with high-res document capturing, and web-based remote assistance systems, which led to 5 publications, 3 patents, and 1 software transfer.

JUNE 2013 – SEPTEMBER 2013

# Research Intern | Nokia Research Center | Berkeley, California

Implemented and parallelized SLIC image segmentation on the Movidius platform, achieving 4x speedup.

MARCH 2005 - MAY 2008

#### Research Engineer | Nexteye Machine Vision | South Korea

Designed and implemented machine vision systems for classifying manufacturing defects. Experienced in the entire lifecycle, from developing computer vision algorithms to deploying and optimizing systems on the factory line.

# Education

AUGUST 2010 - DECEMBER 2016

#### PH.D in Electrical Engineering | University of California, Santa Cruz | Santa Cruz, California

Thesis: Indoor Manhattan Spatial Layout Recovery from Monocular Videos (line-based SfM)

MARCH 2003 - FEBRUARY 2005

## M.S. in Computer Engineering | Sungkyunkwan University | South Korea

Thesis: Structured light based depth edge detection for object shape recovery

MARCH 1999 - FEBRUARY 2003

B.S. in Computer Engineering (GPA 4.12, Rank 5/367) | Sungkyunkwan University | South Korea

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/chelhwon-kim-0a4a5428/

Google Scholar: <a href="https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=cPf0CScAAAAJ&hl=en">https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=cPf0CScAAAAJ&hl=en</a>

Personal website: <a href="https://chelhwon.github.io/">https://chelhwon.github.io/</a>